

Johanna Lonn

Graphic Designer | Web Developer | Office Manager

Johanna has over 13 years of professional experience providing graphic and web design and development services, with particular expertise in graphic and print design, large format printing, package and advertising design, newsletter design, web design and development, database development, HTML/CSS, and photography for a variety of projects. She currently serves as the Office Manager, Graphic Designer and Web Developer for the Archie Held Studio, responsible for supporting the office through efforts that provide value, improve decision-making, capitalize on her strengths, focus on client-centered marketing efforts, and improve the overall quality of business and communication services. She is capable of understanding and completing deadline-driven tasks quickly and accurately, with great attention to detail. In addition to her work for the studio, Johanna provides freelance web and graphic design services to several local businesses including salons, artists and other independent professionals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2008 - Present

Graphic Designer/Web Developer/Office Manager | Archie Held Studio

Responsibilities include evaluating the business, marketing, and communication needs of the studio and determining how to best support those needs; managing graphical web, marketing and communication support services; reviewing business protocol and facilitating improvements; facilitating collaboration between clients and design staff; developing proactive systems and materials to facilitate more efficient marketing efforts; encouraging continual improvement; increasing overall effectiveness of business and marketing products and processes; and ensuring efforts are consistent. Other specific responsibilities include:

- · Manages the production of statements of qualification, annual artist's print catalogue, and presentations
- Prepared and maintains a library of project sheets and boilerplate information
- Designs and develops marketing collateral (print and web)
- Designed and continuously develops the studio's web presence (www.archieheld.com)
- · Develops and coordinates marketing-related activities
- · Personal Assistant duties for owner, Archie Held, including scheduling, coordination, and accounting.
- Manages the general day-to-day running of the office including: invoicing, drafting contracts, copyright
 work, processing purchase orders and RFI's/change orders, gallery and studio inventory, providing pricing
 for artwork, shipping, payroll processing and human resources services for all employees
- · Represents the studio to clients and business associates

2001 - Present

Freelance Graphic Designer/Web Developer | JohannaLonn.com

Provides graphic design and coding services in the development of professional websites (including mobile-friendly sites) for local small businesses including salons, artists, and other professionals. Design work is performed using Photoshop, Illustrator, and Flash and integrated later into Dreamweaver or hand-coded using HTML and/or CSS. Additional services include advanced photo editing/manipulation, business card creation, stationary/logo creation, branding and the creation of a variety other marketing print and web materials.

2006 - 2008

Office Manager/COBRA Assistant | Colt Express Benefits Outsourcing

As Office Manager, responsibilities included providing administrative support to the overall office and Operations Manager. Specific responsibilities included managing office communications and relationships with vendors, designing all office letterhead, processing incoming and outgoing mail, answering and directing calls, and ordering office supplies. As an assistant processor in the COBRA benefits department, responsibilities including the preparation and distribution of COBRA benefit packages and tracking incoming and outgoing COBRA payments.

EDUCATION -

- A.A., Art & Digital Media, Diablo Valley College, in progress
- Advanced Web Design/Development Courses, Team Treehouse, Member since 2013

REFERENCES -

- Candice Clemmons, Marketing Coordinator, HDR Engineering, T: (925) 360-5966
- Andy Drake, Digital Support Developer, Entercom Communications, T: (925) 216-8230